A Guide to the Records of the Virginia Pupil Placement Board, 1957-1966
Library of Virginia
- Series II. Personnel, 1957-1966., Extent: .35 cu. ft. (1 box). (Box 63)
  Arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  - Barker, Lydia E., 1960-1964. (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Bland, Joseph W., 1957-1958. (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Boschen, Hazel M.B., 1957. (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Boyd, Gretchen F., 1962-1966. (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Broaddus, Betty A., 1957. (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - Costin, Frances R., 1960-1966. (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Harris, Eleanor S., 1961. (Box 63, Folder 11)
  - Hilton, Birschell S., 1957-1966. (Box 63, Folder 12)
  - Job Descriptions, 1958-1960. (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - Johnston, Dorothy P., 1958-1966. (Box 63, Folder 14)
  - Johnston, Grace J., 1958-1960. (Box 63, Folder 15)
  - Matthews, Thelma, 1957-1963. (Box 63, Folder 16)
  - Memoranda, 1952-1965. (Box 63, Folder 17)
  - Mock, Evelyn M., 1958-1962. (Box 63, Folder 18)
  - Pickett, Beverley M., 1957-1958. (Box 63, Folder 19)
  - Poteet, George F., 1959. (Box 63, Folder 20)
  - Ragland, Mary W., 1957. (Box 63, Folder 21)
  - Spargo, Jane N., 1957-1966. (Box 63, Folder 22)
  - Taylor, Sally D., 1957-1960. (Box 63, Folder 23)
- Series III. Minutes, 1957-1966., Extent: 2.8 cu. ft. (8 boxes) (Box 64-72)
  This series contains the minutes from the board's meetings; the books contain the official draft of the minutes as the board approved of them, dating from January of 1957 to the boards dissolution in June of 1966. The Board Meeting files contain drafts of the minutes, the meeting agenda and other documents related to that meetings proceedings.
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  - Book 1, 1957 Jan. - 1959 Dec.. (Box 64)
  - Book 2, 1960 Jan. - 1963 June. (Box 64)
  - Book 3, 1963 July - 1964 Nov. (Box 65)
  - Book 4, 1964 Dec. - 1966 June. (Box 65)
  - Board Meeting, 1958 May 19. (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Board Meeting, 1958 June 13. (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Board Meeting, 1958 July 18. (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Board Meeting, 1958 Aug 4. (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - Board Meeting, 1958 Aug 7. (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Board Meeting, 1958 Aug 11. (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Board Meeting, 1958 Aug 25. (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Board Meeting, 1958 Aug 27. (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Board Meeting, 1958 Aug 29. (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Board Meeting, 1958 Sept 12. (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - Board Meeting, 1958 Sept 16. (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - Board Meeting, 1958 Sept 30. (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Board Meeting, 1958 Oct 15. (Box 66, Folder 13)
  - Board Meeting, 1958 Oct 28. (Box 66, Folder 14)
  - Board Meeting, 1958 Nov 25. (Box 66, Folder 15)
  - Board Meeting, 1959 Jan 8. (Box 66, Folder 16)
  - Board Meeting, 1959 Jan 21. (Box 66, Folder 17)
  - Board Meeting, 1959 Feb 11. (Box 66, Folder 18)
  - Board Meeting, 1959 Feb 27. (Box 66, Folder 19)
  - Board Meeting, 1959 Apr 15. (Box 66, Folder 20)
  - Board Meeting, 1959 Apr 29. (Box 66, Folder 21)
  - Board Meeting, 1959 May 13. (Box 66, Folder 22)
  - Board Meeting, 1959 May 25. (Box 66, Folder 23)
  - Board Meeting, 1959 June 15. (Box 66, Folder 24)
  - Board Meeting, 1959 June 19. (Box 66, Folder 25)
  - Board Meeting, 1959 July 15. (Box 66, Folder 26)
  - Board Meeting, 1959 Aug 3. (Box 66, Folder 27)
  - Board Meeting, 1959 Aug 25. (Box 66, Folder 28)
  - Board Meeting, 1959 Aug 28. (Box 66, Folder 29)
  - Board Meeting, 1959 Aug 31. (Box 66, Folder 30)
  - Board Meeting, 1959 Sept 3. (Box 66, Folder 31)
  - Board Meeting, 1959 Sept 9. (Box 66, Folder 32)
  - Board Meeting, 1959 Oct 2. (Box 66, Folder 33)
  - Board Meeting, 1959 Oct 30. (Box 66, Folder 34)
  - Board Meeting, 1959 Dec 1. (Box 66, Folder 35)
  - Board Meeting, 1959 Dec 16. (Box 66, Folder 36)
  - Board Meeting, 1960 Jan 12. (Box 66, Folder 37)
  - Board Meeting, 1960 Jan 19. (Box 66, Folder 38)
  - Board Meeting, 1960 Feb 24. (Box 66, Folder 39)
  - Board Meeting, 1960 Feb 29. (Box 66, Folder 40)
  - Board Meeting, 1960 Mar 24. (Box 66, Folder 41)
  - Board Meeting, 1960 May 25. (Box 66, Folder 42)
  - Board Meeting, 1960 July 25. (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Board Meeting, 1960 Aug 4. (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Board Meeting, 1960 Aug 15. (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Board Meeting, 1960 Aug 29. (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Board Meeting, 1960 Sept 6. (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Board Meeting, 1960 Sept 12. (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - Board Meeting, 1960 Sept 26. (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Board Meeting, 1960 Sept 29. (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Board Meeting, 1960 Oct 10. (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Board Meeting, 1960 Nov 14. (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - Board Meeting, 1960 Dec 22. (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - Board Meeting, 1961 Jan 9. (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - Board Meeting, 1961 Jan 16. (Box 67, Folder 13)
  - Board Meeting, 1961 Feb 13. (Box 67, Folder 14)
  - Board Meeting, 1961 Mar 13. (Box 67, Folder 15)
  - Board Meeting, 1961 Apr 10. (Box 67, Folder 16)
  - Board Meeting, 1961 May. (Box 67, Folder 17)
  - Board Meeting, 1961 June. (Box 67, Folder 18)
  - Board Meeting, 1961 July 11-13. (Box 67, Folder 19)
  - Board Meeting, 1961 July 25. (Box 67, Folder 20)
  - Board Meeting, 1961 July 31. (Box 67, Folder 21)
  - Board Meeting, 1961 Aug 14. (Box 67, Folder 22)
  - Board Meeting, 1961 Aug 18. (Box 67, Folder 23)
  - Board Meeting, 1961 Aug 23. (Box 67, Folder 24)
  - Board Meeting, 1961 Aug 29. (Box 67, Folder 25)
  - Board Meeting, 1961 Sept 5. (Box 67, Folder 26)
  - Board Meeting, 1961 Sept 11. (Box 67, Folder 27)
  - Board Meeting, 1961 Oct. (Box 67, Folder 28)
  - Board Meeting, 1961 Nov 16. (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Board Meeting, 1961 Dec 11. (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Board Meeting, 1962 Jan 8. (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - Board Meeting, 1962 Feb 12. (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Board Meeting, 1962 Mar 12. (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Board Meeting, 1962 Apr 16. (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Board Meeting, 1962 May 14. (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Board Meeting, 1962 June 11-14. (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Board Meeting, 1962 June 20. (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Board Meeting, 1962 June 27. (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - Board Meeting, 1962 July 9. (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - Board Meeting, 1962 Aug 3. (Box 68, Folder 12)
  - Board Meeting, 1962 Aug 13. (Box 68, Folder 13)
  - Board Meeting, 1962 Aug 27. (Box 68, Folder 14)
  - Board Meeting, 1962 Sept 17. (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - Board Meeting, 1962 Oct 8. (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Board Meeting, 1962 Nov 6. (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Board Meeting, 1962 Dec 3. (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - Board Meeting, 1963 Jan 14. (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Board Meeting, 1963 Feb 11. (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - Board Meeting, 1963 Mar 18. (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - Board Meeting, 1963 Apr 8. (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - Board Meeting, 1963 May 15. (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - Board Meeting, 1963 June 4. (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - Board Meeting, 1963 Jun 24-27. (Box 69, Folder 11)
  - Board Meeting, 1963 July 12. (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Board Meeting, 1963 July 23. (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Board Meeting, 1963 Aug 12. (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Board Meeting, 1963 Sept 9. (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Board Meeting, 1963 Sept 16. (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - Board Meeting, 1963 Oct 14. (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - Board Meeting, 1963 Nov 18. (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - Board Meeting, 1963 Dec 9. (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - Board Meeting, 1964 Jan 13. (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - Board Meeting, 1964 Feb 10. (Box 70, Folder 10)
  - Board Meeting, 1964 Mar 9. (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - Board Meeting, 1964 Apr 14. (Box 70, Folder 12)
  - Board Meeting, 1964 May 11. (Box 70, Folder 13)
  - Board Meeting, 1964 June 15-17. (Box 70, Folder 14)
  - Board Meeting, 1964 July 6-9. (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Board Meeting, 1964 Aug 10. (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Board Meeting, 1964 Aug 28. (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Board Meeting, 1964 Sept 14. (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Board Meeting, 1964 Oct 13. (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Board Meeting, 1964 Nov 16. (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Board Meeting, 1964 Dec 14. (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Board Meeting, 1965 Jan 11. (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - Board Meeting, 1965 Feb 8. (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - Board Meeting, 1965 Mar 15. (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - Board Meeting, 1965 Apr 20. (Box 71, Folder 11)
  - Board Meeting, 1965 May. (Box 71, Folder 12)
  - Board Meeting, 1965 June 14. (Box 71, Folder 13)
  - Board Meeting, 1965 June 16. (Box 71, Folder 14)
  - Board Meeting, 1965 July 13. (Box 71, Folder 15)
  - Board Meeting, 1965 July 30. (Box 71, Folder 16)
  - Board Meeting, 1965 Aug 16. (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Board Meeting, 1965 Sept 1. (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - Board Meeting, 1965 Sept 20. (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Board Meeting, 1965 Oct 11. (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Board Meeting, 1965 Nov 15. (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Board Meeting, 1965 Dec 13. (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Board Meeting, 1966 Jan 24. (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - Board Meeting, 1966 Feb 28. (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Board Meeting, 1966 Mar 28. (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - Board Meeting, 1966 Apr 15. (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - Board Meeting, 1966 May. (Box 72, Folder 11)
  - Board Meeting, 1966 June 24. (Box 72, Folder 12)
- Series IV. Legal Files, 1957-1966., 5 cu. ft. (12 boxes) (Box 73-85)
  This series contains the legal files of the Pupil Placement Board created by, Adolphus B. Scott, official legal council. Scott served the board from 1957 until his death in 1964, after Scott's death the board did not hire a replacement attorney, as the board had no authority by that time.
  - Subseries I. Case Files, 1958-1964., 3.6 cu. ft. (8 boxes) (Box 73-81)
    This subseries contains; subpoenas, motions, briefs, memorandums, and limited official trial transcripts, all relating to suits filed against the board or school board in which African-American studens have sought placement in a "White's Only" school. Many of the suits contain multiple plaintiffs, often being known by the student whose name came first alphabetically. Some of the memorandums discuss the rulings made by Judge Walter E. Hoffman, who served the United States District Court for the Eastern District of Virginia, in Norfolk. Judge Hoffman was elected to the Norfolk court by President Eisenhower, and considered it his duty to up hold the precedent set by the national government in regard to desegregation.
    This collection is arranged alphabetically by location. Cities and counties are filled together, counties have been labled as such. Civil Action case numbers accompany folder titles.
    - Alexandria (1770), 1958. (Box 73, Folder 1)
    - Amherst County, 1962. (Box 73, Folder 2)
    - Arlington County (1341), 1958. (Box 73, Folder 3)
    - Charlottesville (51 and 1341), 1956-1957. (Box 73, Folder 4)
    - Chesterfield County (3785 and 3431), 1962-1963. (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Fairfax County (4753 - DeFebio Case), 1957. (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Floyd (1012), 1959-1964. (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Frederick County (9825 and 642), 1963-1965. (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Fredericksburg (3438), 1962-1963. (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Grayson County (721 and 722), 1959-1961. (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Grayson County/Galax (776), 1960-1961. (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Greene County (103), 1963-1964. (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Hampton (595), 1957. (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Hopewell (3554), 1962-1963. (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Isle of Wight County (2559), 1957. (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - King George County (3579), 1963-1964. (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - King George County: Application B-H (3579), 1962. (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - King George County: Application L-W (3579), 1962. (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Loudoun County (2737), 1962-1963. (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Lynchburg (534 and 8722), 1962-1964. (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Lynchburg: Court Publications and Transcripts (8722), 1961-1962. (Box 76, Folder 1)
    - Montgomery County, 1961. (Box 76, Folder 2)
    - Newport News (489 and 642), 1957-1960. (Box 76, Folder 3)
    - Norfolk (2214), 1957-1960. (Box 76, Folder 4)
    - Norfolk: Transcript (2214), 1959. (Box 76, Folder 5)
    - Petersburg (4476), 1965-1966. (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - Powhatan County (3518), 1961-1963. (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Powhatan County (3518 and 8944), 1962-1963. (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Prince Edward County (1333), 1957-1959. (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Prince George County (3536), 1962-1963. (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Prince George County (3822), 1963-1965. (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Prince George County - Applications, 1962. (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Prince George County - Complete File pt. 1 of 2, 1962-1963. (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Prince George County - Complete File pt. 2 of 2, 1962-1963. (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Prince George County - Plaintiff's Exhibits, 1962-1963. (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Prince George County - Transcript, 1963 May 14-15. (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Pulaski County (1052), 1960. (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Pulaski County - Transcript, 1960 Feb 4. (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Richmond (3353), 1957-1962. (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Richmond (2819, 2616, 2699, 3353, 9471, and 8757), 1957-1963. (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Richmond (2819), 1958-1960. (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Roanoke (1093 and 8534), 1959-1963. (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Roanoke - Applications, 1961. (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Roanoke (1093 and 8534), 1959-1963. (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Roanoke - Court Publications, 1961-1962. (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Roanoke County (1095), 1960-1962. (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Roanoke County (1095), 1961. (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Shenandoah County (641), 1962. (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Suffolk/Nansemond County (2550, 2551, 2552), 1957-1959. (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Warren County, 1961. (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - Waynesboro, 1960. (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - West Point (3365), 1961-1963. (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - West Point - Transcripts and Applications, 1961. (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Winchester (629), 1961-1963. (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Winchester - Transcript, 1961. (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - York County (898), 1962-1963. (Box 81, Folder 3)
  - Subseries II. Correspondence - Miscellaneous, 1957-1964., .1 cu. ft (1 folder) (Box 81, Folder 4)
    This subseries contains correspondence recieved and sent by the office of attorney Adolphus B. Scott.
    This subseries is arranged by case file, as recieved by the agency.
  - Subseries III. Trial Transcripts, 1958-1962., .7 cu. ft (2 boxes) (Box 82-83)
    Within this subseries are official transcripts from public hearings which were held in order to decisivly settle placement protests.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by location, with counties appearing in box 82 and cities in box 83.
    - Amherst County, 1962 Aug 14. (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Arlington County, 1958 Sept 2. (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Arlington County, 1958 Sept 3. (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Arlington County, 1958 Sept 4. (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Chesterfield County, 1962. (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - King George County, 1962. (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Montgomery County, 1961 Aug 11. (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - Prince William County, 1961 Aug 14. (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Roanoke County, 1961 Aug 22. (Box 82, Folder 9)
    - Stafford County, 1961 Aug 29. (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - Arlington, 1958 Aug 12. (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Arlington, 1958 Aug 18. (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Arlington, 1958 Aug 19. (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Arlington, 1958 Aug 29. (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Fredericksburg, 1961 Aug 14. (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Fredericksburg, 1962 Aug 3. (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Hopewell, 1962 Aug 14. (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - Lynchburg, 1961 Aug 23. (Box 83, Folder 8)
    - Lynchburg, 1962 Aug 3. (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - Newport News, 1959 July 21. (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - Newport News, 1959 Dec 1. (Box 83, Folder 11)
    - Richmond, 1960 Feb 24. (Box 83, Folder 12)
    - Richmond, 1960 Sept 12. (Box 83, Folder 13)
    - Richmond, 1962 Aug 3. (Box 83, Folder 14)
    - Richmond - Exhibits, 1961. (Box 83, Folder 15)
    - Roanoke, 1961 Aug 23. (Box 83, Folder 16)
    - Waynesboro, 1960 Sept 26. (Box 83, Folder 17)
    - West Point, 1961 Aug 29. (Box 83, Folder 18)
  - Subseries IV. Student Records, Undated., .7 cu. ft. (2 boxes) (Box 84-85)
    This subseries contains student education records, comprized of various test scores and report cards. Restricted envelopes contain student test scores and/or grades and are to remain sealed for 75 years from the date of creation in accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA) and Codes of Virginia 2.2-3705.4 and 2.2-3705.1. Folders are arranged alphabetically by location, forms within the folders are arranged alphabetically by students last name
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by student last names.
    - Augins, Charles Levering, Undated. (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Brooks, Gloria, Undated. (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Boswell, Gary, Undated. (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Brevard, Erleen (Eavlene), Undated. (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Carmichael, Dwight, Undated. (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Carmichael, Lessie Ruth, Undated. (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Carter, Arnette B., Undated. (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Crutchfield, Deloris, Undated. (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - Crutchfield, George, Undated. (Box 84, Folder 9)
    - Deskins, Ronald, Undated. (Box 84, Folder 10)
    - Eldridge, Robert A., III, Undated. (Box 84, Folder 11)
    - Faggins, Algie Darrell, Undated. (Box 84, Folder 12)
    - Hallion, Deidra G., Undated. (Box 84, Folder 13)
    - Hamm, Leslie, Undated. (Box 84, Folder 14)
    - Harrison, Barbara A., Undated. (Box 84, Folder 15)
    - Holmes, Yvonne H., Undated. (Box 84, Folder 16)
    - Hunter, Warren G., Jr., Undated. (Box 84, Folder 17)
    - Jones, Michael G., Undated. (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Moore, George H., Jr., Undated. (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Moore, Peggy Ann, Undated. (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Nelson, George T., Undated. (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Newman, Lance Dwight, Undated. (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Norris, Sheila, Undated. (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Rowe, Gloria E., Undated. (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - Strother, Joyce, Undated. (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - Thompson, Gloria Delores, Undated. (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - Thompson, Stephen, Undated. (Box 85, Folder 10)
    - Turner, Anita, Undated. (Box 85, Folder 11)
    - Turner, Louis George, Undated. (Box 85, Folder 12)
    - Turner, Melvin H., Undated. (Box 85, Folder 13)
    - Walker, Burnell H., Undated. (Box 85, Folder 14)
    - Walker, Helen Dianne, Undated. (Box 85, Folder 15)
    - Williams, Janet, Undated. (Box 85, Folder 16)
- Series V. Maps, 1957-1966., Extent: (1 box). (Box 86)
  This series contains maps which have locations of schools and often applicants's homes marked on them, sometimes there is one map per student other times there is one map with all locations. These maps were, generally, created to illustrate the distance from the school an applicant was currently enrolled and the one they were requesting transfer to.
  This series is arranged alphabetically by location, cities and counties are combined. This box also contains oversized materials which have been seperated from their parent folders.
  - A, 1957-1961. (Box 86, Folder 1)
  - B-C, 1953-1962. (Box 86, Folder 2)
  - D, 1961. (Box 86, Folder 3)
  - F-H, 1958-1963. (Box 86, Folder 4)
  - K-L, 1957-1961. (Box 86, Folder 5)
  - M-P, 1957-1961. (Box 86, Folder 6)
  - R, 1959-1961. (Box 86, Folder 7)
  - S-W, 1958-1961. (Box 86, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 1957-1961. (Box 86, Folder 9)
  - Virginia, 1957-1961. (Box 86, Folder 10)
  - Seibel Cartoon - Enlarged, 1957. (Box 86, Folder 11)
  - Exhibit in Waynesboro Appeal Case, 1960. (Box 86, Folder 12)
  - Maps - Oversized, 1957-1966. (Drawer L Cab. 56 13, Folder 13)
- Series VI. Applications, 1959-1966., Extent: 224.35 cu. ft. (641 boxes). (Box 87-728)
  Two subseries. This series contains applications for student placement. It is the largest series in the collection as the placement of students represents the main function of the Pupil Placement Board. The applications were completed by parents or guardians who desired to either place a new student in a Virginia school or move a current student to a different school. Each application is the top page of a triplicate form that includes the name of the student to be placed, the county for which enrollment is requested, the year the student is to be enrolled, the student's address, years of school attendance, sex, birthdate, health status, and any aptitudes. The applications do not address race but some are appended with a particular student's race noted. A section at the bottom of each certificate reserved for the use of the local school board contains space for comments concerning the pupil and the placement recommendation. The board section also contains the signatures of representatives from the state school board, the local school board, the school principal, and a rubber stamp impression of Birchel S. Hilton signature, the executive secretary of the Pupil Placement Board. Hilton served as Superintendent of Shenandoah County Schools and subsequently resigned his position after a very public battle with the county's school board over budget issues and his connections to the Department of Education, months later he joined the Pupil Placement Board.
  - Subseries I. Special, 1959-1966., 6.3 cu. ft. (18 boxes) (Box 87-105)
    This subseries contains the applications the Pupil Placement Board referred to as "Special," these applications belonged to the students whose parents desired their children to receive a desegregated and equal public education and were not willing to wait for the state to voluntarily integrate schools. The special applications often contain a hand written note stating whether the transfer was approved, denied, or not considered. Depending upon location applications were also accompanied by a copy of an administrative transfer, or there were included lists of all transfers with students name, school where student was previously enrolled and location of current enrollment. There are also multiple application for the same student, usually from different years indicating the parent continued to petition for a transfer. A large number of applications contain the phrase "I do not wish my child to attend a racially segregated school," so something similar.
    This subseries is arranged alphabetically by location. The folder for each location is then arranged alphabetically by student's last name, thereunder by first name. Applications are not chronological, except if there is more than one for a single student.
    - Accomack County, 1964-1965. (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Albemarle County, 1963-1964. (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Amelia County, 1964-1965. (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Amherst County, 1961-1965. (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Appomattox County, 1965-1966. (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Arlington County, 1959-1960. (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Augusta County, 1961-1966. (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Bath County, 1964-1965. (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Bedford County, 1965-1966. (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Bland County, 1965. (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - Botetourt County, 1965. (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - Brunswick County, 1964-1965. (Box 87, Folder 12)
    - Campbell County, 1964-1965. (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Caroline County, 1965. (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - Carroll County, 1960/1964. (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - Charles City County, 1963-1965. (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Chesterfield County (A-B), 1963-1966. (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Chesterfield County (C-G), 1963-1966. (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Chesterfield County (H-Me.), 1961-1965. (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Chesterfield County (Mi.-Y), 1961-1965. (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - Clarke County, 1965. (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - Culpeper County, 1963-1965. (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - Dickenson County, 1962. (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - Dinwiddie County, 1963-1964. (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - Essex - Middlesex County, 1965. (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Fairfax County, 1959-1960. (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - Fauquier County, 1964-1965. (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - Franklin County, 1964-1965. (Box 89, Folder 9)
    - Floyd County, 1961-1965. (Box 89, Folder 10)
    - Frederick County, 1962-1965. (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Giles County, 1964-1965. (Box 90, Folder 2)